we need to
store the dates from our movies hash
into an array
and then we're going to output each of
them
so i'll initialize an array called dates
and place each of the values from our
hash as an element in this dates array
[Music]
and we can go ahead and get rid of this
hash
now we need to print each element of our
dates array
we'll do this using array element
reference
and we can access an element of an array
by its index
the first element of the array has index
the second element has index 1 and so on
you can see the syntax for array element
reference
on line three we use a pair of square
brackets
and pass in the index of the element
that we want to reference
now let's run our file and we expect to
output
1975.
and that's what we see
so let's go back to our text editor and
output each of the other dates in our
array as well
now it's important to note that the last
index of an array
is always going to be one less than its
size
in this case our dates array has five
elements
because array indexes are 0 based
the last index of our array is going to
be 4.
so let's run our file and we'll see all
5 years
or elements of our array output
remember that arrays have a zero-based
index
and element reference is an easy way to
access any element in an array